Guide to the Student Life at Yale Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Photographs and pictures of student life, Yale University, circa 1779-1988; Series I
  - Rooms
    - South College, pre-1879 (Box 14, Folder 492)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1880s (Box 14, Folder 493)
    - Thalsted Myers, Circa 1881 (Box 14, Folder 494)
    - Stephen Merrill Clement, Circa 1881-1882 (Box 14, Folder 688)
    - Room # 11, South College, south entry, Circa 1882-1883 (Box 14, Folder 495)
    - J. Foote, Circa 1883 (Box 14, Folder 496)
    - Unidentified, 1883 (Box 14, Folder 497)
    - Wyllis Terry and Joseph Vernon, 1885 (Box 14, Folder 689)
    - W. T. Williams, Y. 1885S -- either 135 College or 71 West Divinity, Circa 1885 (Box 14, Folder 498)
    - Hall (Box 14, Folder 498)
    - J.E. Wing, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 499)
    - William Burton Goodwin, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 500)
    - H.B. Ferris -- Room #44, Connecticut Hall, 1886-1887 (Box 14, Folder 501)
    - Donald McCormick -- 192 York Street, 1886-1887 (Box 14, Folder 502)
    - H. Reynolds 1887s -- 43 College St. (Box 14, Folder 503)
    - Donald McCormick -- 148 Farnam Hall (Box 14, Folder 504-505)
    - S. H. McCrea, Y. 1888S -- 36 Elm Street, Circa 1888 (Box 14, Folder 506)
    - Henry Tweedy -- South College study, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 507)
    - Donald McCormick -- H. M. Bishop, 120 North College, 1889-1890 (Box 15, Folder 508-510)
    - 43 College Street, Circa 1890 (Box 15, Folder 511)
    - Henry Tweedy -- Lawrence Hall, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 512)
    - R.K. Dickerman and J.H. Field, 161 Farnam Hall, 1890-1892 (Box 15, Folder 513)
    - Unidentified, 1890s (Box 15, Folder 514-516)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1892 (Box 15, Folder 517)
    - Unidentified, 1892-1893 (Box 15, Folder 518)
    - Frank Hooker -- Old Brick Row, 1892-1896 (Box 15, Folder 519)
    - T.L. Bristol -- 162 Farnam Hall, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 520)
    - Richard Goodman -- Connecticut Hall, 1893 (Box 16, Folder 521)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1893 (Box 16, Folder 522)
    - Rooms (coned) (Box 16, Folder 522)
    - Grant Mitchell, Jr., 1893-1894 (Box 16, Folder 523)
    - F.B. Solley -- 228 Durfee Hall, 1894 (Box 16, Folder 524)
    - A. Dater, 1895 (Box 16, Folder 525)
    - A.J. Gilmore -- 36 Elm Street, Circa 1895 (Box 16, Folder 526)
    - 53 Vanderbilt Hall, Circa 1895 (Box 16, Folder 527)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1895-1899 (Box 16, Folder 528)
    - Norman King -- 117 Wall Street, Circa 1895-1896 (Box 16, Folder 529)
    - Edward L. Smith, Circa 1897 (Box 16, Folder 530)
    - 78 South Middle (Connecticut Hall), Circa 1897 (Box 16, Folder 531)
    - Francis P. Garvan, Circa 1897 (Box 16, Folder 532)
    - Edward R. Ingraham, Circa 1898 (Box 16, Folder 533)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1899 (Box 16, Folder 534)
    - [Hutchinson?], Circa 1900 (Box 16, Folder 535)
    - H. Moore -- [Vanderbilt?], Circa 1900 (Box 16, Folder 536)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1900 (Box 16, Folder 537)
    - North College, pre-1901 (Box 16, Folder 538)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1901 (Box 16, Folder 539)
    - 54 Vanderbilt Hall, 1901-1902 (Box 16, Folder 540)
    - 46 Vanderbilt Hall, 1902-1903 (Box 16, Folder 541)
    - R. Norton -- 22 College Street, Circa 1902 (Box 16, Folder 542)
    - "Jolly eight" sitting room, Circa 1903 (Box 16, Folder 543)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1903 (Box 16, Folder 544)
    - Caleb W. O'Connor, 1904 Law, Circa 1904 (Box 16, Folder 545)
    - 339 White Hall, Circa 1905 (Box 16, Folder 546)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1905 (Box 16, Folder 547)
    - York Street -- Old Freshman Row, 1906-1907 (Box 17, Folder 548)
    - 225 Crown Street, 1907-1908 (Box 17, Folder 549)
    - Crown Street, 1907-1908 (Box 17, Folder 550)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1909 (Box 17, Folder 551)
    - Charles Price and Charles Glover -- Vanderbilt Hall, Circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 552)
    - Apartment of "Attic Philosophers" in South Sheffield Tower, Circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 553)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 554)
    - Harvard, Circa 1911 (Box 17, Folder 555)
    - Unidentified, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 556)
    - Leonard Doyle, Circa 1914 (Box 17, Folder 557)
    - [Waiting room?], Circa 1930 (Box 17, Folder 559)
      - 787 Memorial Quadrangle, 1921 (Box 17, Folder 558)
    - Unidentified, 1930s (Box 17, Folder 560)
    - 96 Wall Street, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 561)
    - Pierson College, Circa 1950 (Box 17, Folder 562)
    - Unidentified, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 563)
    - Unidentified, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 564)
    - Davenport College, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 565)
    - Timothy Dwight College, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 566)
    - Old Campus, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 567)
    - Silliman College, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 568)
    - Trumbull College, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 569)
  - Rush (Box 17, Folder 569)
  - "The Great Russian Conflict -- Battle of Shirtzka", 1877 (Box 17, Folder 570)
  - Rush
    - Washington's Birthday, 1894-1897 (Box 17, Folder 571)
    - Washington's Birthday, 1900-1911 (Box 17, Folder 572)
  - Security -- substitute guard at Trumbull College, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 573)
  - Security -- campus policeman at Trumbull College, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 574)
  - Snow Scenes
    - Seniors in Vanderbilt Court, 1900-1920 (Box 17, Folder 575)
    - [Berkeley College?], 1938 (Box 17, Folder 576)
    - Old Campus, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 577)
    - 1962 (Box 17, Folder 578)
    - Snow sculptures, pre-1950 (Box 17, Folder 579)
    - Snowball riot (Box 17, Folder 580-581)
    - Snowball fight, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 582)
  - Sports spectators
    - Baseball, 1897 (Box 17, Folder 583)
    - Football
      - (drawing), Circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 584)
      - Circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 585)
      - Circa 1910-1920 (Box 17, Folder 586)
      - Circa 1940 (Box 17, Folder 587)
      - 1943 (Box 17, Folder 588)
      - Princeton-Yale game rally, "Put a Tiger in the trash", Circa 1960s (Box 17, Folder 589)
      - Circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 590)
    - General, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 591)
    - General, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 592)
    - General, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 593)
  - Street scenes
    - Elm Street, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 17, Folder 594)
    - Parades, Circa 1900-1920 (Box 17, Folder 595)
    - 1920s (Box 17, Folder 596)
    - 1930s (Box 18, Folder 597)
    - Vendors, Circa 1930s (Box 18, Folder 598)
    - Waiting in line for hockey tickets, Circa 1930 (Box 18, Folder 599)
    - Shoe shine boys, 1930s-1940s (Box 18, Folder 600)
    - [Whitney Avenue?], 1936 (Box 18, Folder 601)
    - Circa 1937 (Box 18, Folder 602)
    - 1940s (Box 18, Folder 603)
    - College Street, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 604)
    - Political posters for Dewey, by J.G. Hamilton, Y. 1949, Circa 1949 (Box 18, Folder 605)
    - 1950s (Box 18, Folder 606)
    - Vendor, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 607)
    - Student on motorcycle, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 608)
  - Student activities
    - Filming a movie, 1920s (Box 18, Folder 609)
    - Newspaper article -- "Do Yale men drink?" (AP), 1930 (Box 18, Folder 610)
    - Budget drive, 1937-1942 (Box 18, Folder 611)
    - Printing, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 612)
    - Unidentified, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 613)
    - Layout -- newspaper or yearbook (Box 18, Folder 614)
    - Saxophone section [jazz ensemble], 1962 (Box 18, Folder 615)
    - Singing group, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 616)
    - Sorting pictures -- newspaper or yearbook (Box 18, Folder 617)
  - SYBC-TV, student-owned and operated television station, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 617A)
    Two students (Arthur Espy and Harry Benatovich) do take-off on "Dragnet" radio mystery program.
  - Tang Cup Competition, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 618)
  - Tang Cup Competition, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 619)
  - Tap Day
    - Circa 1890s (Box 18, Folder 620)
    - 1929-1930 (Box 18, Folder 622)
    - Circa 1900-1910 (Box 18, Folder 621)
    - 1937 (Box 18, Folder 623)
    - 1938 (Box 18, Folder 624)
    - 1940-1950 (Box 18, Folder 625)
  - Vehicles
    - Automobiles
      - 1900-1910 (Box 18, Folder 626)
      - 1920s (Box 18, Folder 627)
      - 1934 (Box 18, Folder 628)
    - Bicycles
      - at Hamilton Park, 1879 (Box 18, Folder 629)
      - 1939-1944 (Box 18, Folder 630)
      - 1950s (Box 18, Folder 631)
    - Motorcycle with sidecar, 1920s (Box 18, Folder 632)
    - Yalies on a trolley car, Circa 1924 (Box 18, Folder 633)
    - "Spicy Horror Tales" truck, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 634)
  - War Years
    - Civil War
      - Secession flag riot, 1861 January 20 (Box 18, Folder 635)
      - Unidentified Yale man in uniform (Box 18, Folder 636)
    - Spanish-American War-Yale platoon, Battery A at Niantic, CT (Box 18, Folder 637)
    - World War II
      - Applying for sugar ration cards, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 638)
      - Donating blood, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 639)
      - Enlisting and registering for draft, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 640)
      - Learning firefighting, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 641)
      - Life magazine photos, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 642)
      - Howland Prize to Field Marshall Sir John Greer Dill, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 642A)
        See also: Drawer 17, folder 59.
      - Yale aide helping apply plaster cast, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 643)
      - V-E day, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 644)
  - Wooden Spoon presentation, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 645)
  - Yale Station scenes
    - Fayerweather Hall, Circa 1910 (Box 18, Folder 646)
    - Fayerweather Hall, 1920s (Box 18, Folder 647)
    - 1938 (Box 18, Folder 648)
    - 1950s (Box 18, Folder 647)
    - Mid-1950s (Box 18, Folder 650)
    - Mail Call (drawing), Undated (Box 18, Folder 651)
- Oversize, Series II
  - American Conference of English Professors, Publications at Oxford, 19? (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Banner, 1850s-1860s (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Yale Banner and Potpouri -- Drawings (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Biennial examinations, Circa 1850 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Branford dining hall, Circa 1970 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Calcium Light Night
    - 1907 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons: "Hopkins and the King" artist Troy Kinney, Y. 1901, Circa 1901 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Classes
    - Chemistry (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Chemical Engineering (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Class day, Circa 1905 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Mechanical Engineering (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Metallurgical Engineering (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Professor Blum in SSS 114, Circa 1970 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Lab Science, Circa 1910 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Turkey Count", Winter, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Costumed Students (Group), Circa 1898 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - College Courant board
    - 1902, 1903, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - 1914, 1916, 1917, 1918 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Dances
    - Armory Decorated for the Prom, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Prom Group, Circa 1912 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Dinner, Yale-China, 1912 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Engineering Exhibit, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Freshman Activities Committee, 1957-1961 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Faculty
    - 1916 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Romantic Languages and Faculty Literatures (French) (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Germanic Language and Literature, 1925-1926 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Harkness Hoot, 1932-1933 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - India: Laws injustice in, Circa 1800 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Industrial Administration, 1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Juries, Cartoons and News Clippings of, 1861-1891 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Yale Law Journal (editorial board), 1908-1909 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Yale Literary Magazine
    - 1901, 1931, 1932, 1933 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - 1914 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Kunkel, Beverly W. Y 1901S, Pen and ink Drawings of Yale (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Buildings, Circa 1901 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Moody Summer School, Yale Quarters Northfield, Mass. with 31 students, 1888 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - New Haven Hospital? (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - News, 1874, 1916, 1931, 1932, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Planting class -- Planting Ivy, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Yale Plates (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Play (Book and Snake?), Circa 1908 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Potpourri, 1909-1910 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Records, 1908, 1931, 1932, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Yale Record Board, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - "Rights of Spring" Omega Lamda Chi (Not a Club) (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Rush (Sheffield), 1902, 1912, 1920, undated (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Rush (Sophmore Fence) Washington's Birthday, 1906-1909 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Yale Scientific Monthly (Board)
    - 1896-1918 (Box 22, Folder 43-46)
  - Flag Secession Riot, 1861 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Student Rooms
    - (1830-1833) (2) Raphael Reproductions, (2) 19th and 18th Century Engravings (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Circa 1900 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - room of Edwin C. Northrup and Sheldon Wardell, Class of 1904, Circa 1900-1904 (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - Sugar Rationing in WWII (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - Supreme Court, U.S. (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous Unidentified Group Shots (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - "Yale Commons", Circa 1906 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Pen and ink drawing, captioned "96 Days in the Commons". On reverse: "Decennial Record 1896".
  - Yale Daily News editors, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 53)
- Folio, Series III
  - Freshman initiation, Circa 1869 (Box DR17F59)
  - Junior Prom-illustration in Harper's, 1893 (Box DR17F59)
  - Senior Prom, 1910, 1914, [1947?] (Box DR17F59)
  - Christmas Dinner [Boy's Club?], 1937? (Box DR17F59)
  - WWII -- presentation of Howland Prize to Field Marshall Sir John Greer Dill, Woolsey Hall (Box DR17F59)
    See also: box 18, folder 642A.
  - Charcoal drawing by Ramus, undated (Box DR17F59)
  - WWII -- "Pass in review," New Haven Green, 1945? (Box DR17F59)
  - WWII -- "Off we go", 1945? (Box DR17F59)
  - Collage (Box DR32F101)
  - Mory's [?], Circa 1900 (Box DR17F59)
    Pen and ink drawing by Henry H. Christian (Y1901)
- Slides, Series IV
  - Commencement, Undated (Box 24)
  - Geology Field Work (Box 24)
- Photograph album, possibly of H.H. Tweedy, documenting student life at Yale, circa 1891; Accession 19ND-A-465
  - Photograph album, circa 1891 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Photograph album of George Bates Hatch, circa 1895; Accession 1993-A-074
  - Photograph album of George Bates Hatch, circa 1895 (Box 1)
- Photograph album of the 1936 Barn Party, Accession 2001-A-058
  - Photograph album of the 1936 Barn Party (Box 1)
- Photograph album by O. Dexter Covell, documenting student life and athletics at Yale University, 1910-1913; Accession 2001-A-059
  - Photograph album by O. Dexter Covell, documenting student life and athletics at Yale University, 1910-1913 (Box 1)
- "Innocence at Large," a photograph album of Henry S. Durand (1881), while visiting the campus, Accession 2003-A-159
  - "Innocence at Large," a photograph album of Henry S. Durand (1881), while visiting the campus, Undated (Box 1)
- Photographic negatives of George P. Nevitt documenting student life at Yale, 1915-1918; Accession 2008-A-010
  - Negatives, 1915-1918 (Box 1)
- Photograph album of Joseph Morey (1899), 1895-1899; Accession 2008-A-095
  - Photograph album of Joseph Morey (1899), 1895-1899 (Box 1)